<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Life on Declarative</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Life on Declarative</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 21:43:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Macintosh</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2025/12/the-macintosh-powerbook-g3.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 21:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2025/12/the-macintosh-powerbook-g3.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/AVvXsEgixSQC12K_8g6Iuy7DGX_UJO2WAzhXJyo46J5n-joYbIYM2HfXMBfBFa8EaBeDc10Rw2MeN46AgJfxUfz-z7PlySy_kvNQrsM9fEbrahEdmRjxd7JOp3ubsnVBkbCyvDcy5VDPLHTd4LFQ4-yRgisdLAsiz4rFEP-Xc6ZxBArXPQ5GzxoakXBTcpeE3LI&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/AVvXsEgixSQC12K_8g6Iuy7DGX_UJO2WAzhXJyo46J5n-joYbIYM2HfXMBfBFa8EaBeDc10Rw2MeN46AgJfxUfz-z7PlySy_kvNQrsM9fEbrahEdmRjxd7JOp3ubsnVBkbCyvDcy5VDPLHTd4LFQ4-yRgisdLAsiz4rFEP-Xc6ZxBArXPQ5GzxoakXBTcpeE3LI=w640-h480&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I love the Macintosh. A lot.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Even though I wasn&amp;rsquo;t really exposed to these computers until 2015 when my dad bought a MacBook Air, my appreciation for them runs deep. It&amp;rsquo;s why in middle school I rocked a 5th generation iPod nano - the only Apple product I could really afford at the time beg for as a birthday gift.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My path to computing started elsewhere, though. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.skushagra.com/2024/02/career-optimism-history.html&#34;&gt;My first computer was a netbook running Windows XP - half a gig of RAM, 64GB storage, and an Intel Atom processor&lt;/a&gt;. That netbook became my introduction to Linux, Bash scripting, and the command line - not by choice, but by necessity.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mainframe. Cloud. iPadOS 26 Mobile Productivity Setup.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2025/09/mainframe-computing.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 02:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2025/09/mainframe-computing.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/IMG_0141.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/IMG_0141.png&#34; alt=&#34;Image&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the world of developers and engineers, a spirited debate often rages over which operating system reigns supreme. You&amp;rsquo;ll hear Mac users praise macOS, Windows loyalists defend their OS, and Linux aficionados swear by their distro, convinced it&amp;rsquo;s the one true way.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I believe this passion stems from two core ideas:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Group Identity:&lt;/strong&gt; We&amp;rsquo;re wired to identify with a group. Mac users see themselves as a group, Windows users as another, and Linux users — especially those dedicated to a specific distro — most definitely feel like a tribe. This shared identity fuels the belief that their OS is the &amp;ldquo;right&amp;rdquo; one.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Side Projects and Life Updates</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2024/04/side-projects-and-life-updates.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 01:03:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2024/04/side-projects-and-life-updates.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/5banner.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/5banner.png&#34; alt=&#34;Image&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;side-projects&#34;&gt;Side Projects&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ad my own thesis wraps up and I get a bit more time to pursue other avenues, I am trying to get into more side projects as well as start some of my own again. I felt that there needed to be a fine balance between my actual academic work, side projects, and other hobbies altogether (like photography) so that I do not burn myself out doing one thing only.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metamorphosis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2024/03/metamorphosis.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 00:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2024/03/metamorphosis.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/newsletter4fin.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/newsletter4fin.png&#34; alt=&#34;Image&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Slightly late blog update this week, owing mainly to the amounts of midterms and the thesis progress that had to be made last week. However, we are back and kicking: and I hope that I will be able to keep this momentum up next week as well. In today’s newsletter, I would love to highlight some fun code I wrote for my Honors Thesis last semester.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The banner for this newsletter was taken on my trip to Washington D.C. Fall 2023, during the U.S. Census Department’s Justice Week Event. I was one of the 6 people who worked on &lt;a href=&#34;https://suobset.github.io/assert&#34;&gt;ASSERT&lt;/a&gt;, a GIS Web-App that directs emergency responders (like Eversource, National Grid) to counties that are more vulnerable to energy inequity. A lot of data processing and web development later, we were able to successfully demo our product, which earnwed us a spot on the Census Department’s &lt;a href=&#34;https://opportunity.census.gov/showcase/?year=2023&amp;amp;partner-agency=Department+of+Energy&#34;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Career Optimism &amp; History</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2024/02/career-optimism-history.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 19:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2024/02/career-optimism-history.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/newsletter3.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/newsletter3.png&#34; alt=&#34;Image&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This newsletter is a special one to me: it is the third week that I am writing something down on this platform without fail, and thus building up the momentum to continue doing the same for a longer period of time. The issues that come with scheduling problems, or a general lack of motivation towards doing something start to dwindle by the time it is the third week of committing to a new habit.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Debugxiety</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2023/12/debugxiety.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 21:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2023/12/debugxiety.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;(noun) /dɪˌbʌɡzaɪ.əti/&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Definition: The apprehensive and uneasy feeling experienced by a programmer when faced with the prospect of executing or testing code, particularly after investing a significant amount of time in its creation, due to the anticipation of potential errors, bugs, or the need for extensive debugging.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Example: Sarah hesitated to run the program she had been tirelessly working on for days, overcome by a wave of debugxiety as she feared encountering unforeseen issues that might demand prolonged debugging sessions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Liminal Spaces: the art of being in, and appreciating the in-between.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2023/08/liminal-spaces-art-of-being-in-and.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2023/08/liminal-spaces-art-of-being-in-and.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;this-is-an-attempt-at-documenting-what-has-been-long-gone-by-and-yet-seems-coming-right-across-the-horizon-this-is-a-story-of-a-particular-phase-of-my-own-life-how-it-has-been-influenced-by-my-past-and-how-it-delves-into-one-of-my-favorite-aesthetics-of-all-time-this-will-also-be-an-attempt-to-capture-my-version-of-that-aesthetic&#34;&gt;This is an attempt at documenting what has been long gone by, and yet seems coming right across the horizon. This is a story of a particular phase of my own life, how it has been influenced by my past, and how it delves into one of my favorite aesthetics of all time. This will also be an attempt to capture my version of that aesthetic.&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/AVvXsEh1JwxXhIDeuGAKZ3DMGZ8UbWl85OQILzR7UU1Vj7GanOVUiQpAV0JnDiFte5Udvt8cnNUEpiQfrporzhkOJS3Wdy_yadBOyMHCE5fz9hdGfnfo0tWf4pneX_2YWCd_NWKJuQBaN7NNKDmKMCge6QsAoIytRAiZTfJEW0XOAt7GVmle_p9gcnacsRn12h0&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/AVvXsEh1JwxXhIDeuGAKZ3DMGZ8UbWl85OQILzR7UU1Vj7GanOVUiQpAV0JnDiFte5Udvt8cnNUEpiQfrporzhkOJS3Wdy_yadBOyMHCE5fz9hdGfnfo0tWf4pneX_2YWCd_NWKJuQBaN7NNKDmKMCge6QsAoIytRAiZTfJEW0XOAt7GVmle_p9gcnacsRn12h0=w640-h360&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The beginning of what would culminate into a series of developing multiple aspects into what my life would really turn out to be started right around the corner of me transitioning from my High School phase to my University phase; at a time when every single person on the planet was transitioning away from life as they had known into one that was being navigated in the midst of a global pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
