<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aesthetics on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/aesthetics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aesthetics on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/aesthetics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dreamlike Uncanniness, and Data Bending</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2024/02/dreamlike-uncanniness-and-data-bending.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2024/02/dreamlike-uncanniness-and-data-bending.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There have been quite a few times when I have talked about aesthetics, and I still believe that they are the best way to express myself. I have a &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/blog/liminal-spaces-art-of-appreciating&#34;&gt;post here from last year diving into Liminal Spaces&lt;/a&gt;, and to this day they capture the feeling of loneliness and eerieness perfectly.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A lot of the pictures I take pertain to outdoor Liminal Spaces. It is an interest that started during the Pandemic lockdowns, especially in a context where I was joining online Zoom meetings from the other corner of the globe. Going from interacting with over 15-20 people at a time on Discord to absolute silence at 4AM on the click of a button, I did not yet realize that I was living in a Liminal Space.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Liminal Spaces: the art of being in, and appreciating the in-between.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2023/08/liminal-spaces-art-of-being-in-and.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2023/08/liminal-spaces-art-of-being-in-and.html</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;this-is-an-attempt-at-documenting-what-has-been-long-gone-by-and-yet-seems-coming-right-across-the-horizon-this-is-a-story-of-a-particular-phase-of-my-own-life-how-it-has-been-influenced-by-my-past-and-how-it-delves-into-one-of-my-favorite-aesthetics-of-all-time-this-will-also-be-an-attempt-to-capture-my-version-of-that-aesthetic&#34;&gt;This is an attempt at documenting what has been long gone by, and yet seems coming right across the horizon. This is a story of a particular phase of my own life, how it has been influenced by my past, and how it delves into one of my favorite aesthetics of all time. This will also be an attempt to capture my version of that aesthetic.&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/AVvXsEh1JwxXhIDeuGAKZ3DMGZ8UbWl85OQILzR7UU1Vj7GanOVUiQpAV0JnDiFte5Udvt8cnNUEpiQfrporzhkOJS3Wdy_yadBOyMHCE5fz9hdGfnfo0tWf4pneX_2YWCd_NWKJuQBaN7NNKDmKMCge6QsAoIytRAiZTfJEW0XOAt7GVmle_p9gcnacsRn12h0&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/images/AVvXsEh1JwxXhIDeuGAKZ3DMGZ8UbWl85OQILzR7UU1Vj7GanOVUiQpAV0JnDiFte5Udvt8cnNUEpiQfrporzhkOJS3Wdy_yadBOyMHCE5fz9hdGfnfo0tWf4pneX_2YWCd_NWKJuQBaN7NNKDmKMCge6QsAoIytRAiZTfJEW0XOAt7GVmle_p9gcnacsRn12h0=w640-h360&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The beginning of what would culminate into a series of developing multiple aspects into what my life would really turn out to be started right around the corner of me transitioning from my High School phase to my University phase; at a time when every single person on the planet was transitioning away from life as they had known into one that was being navigated in the midst of a global pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
